<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>psyc2001</title>
<link>https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.353</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 04:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Week 1: Installing software and getting your Quarto Blog working</title>
  <dc:creator>Matt Crump</dc:creator>
  <link>https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/1_Getting_started/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>As we discussed in our meeting a goal for this week is for everyone to get a Quarto blog up and running. You will use this throughout the semester as a lab journal. Every week this blog will be a place where you place your work (along with making notes for yourself about what you are doing).</p>
<p>We will use R, R Studio, Quarto, and Github to create the blog. These very same tools will be used for several other purposes including coding experiments and analysing data from them.</p>
<p>This post contains instructions for getting a quarto blog up and running. If you can’t get something to work and have spend more than 30 minutes trying to solve the problem, then please email me and I will help you!</p>
<section id="setting-up-your-quarto-blog" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="setting-up-your-quarto-blog">Setting up your quarto blog</h2>
<p>I wrote a whole blog post about how to do this a year ago. Here is the link. All of the steps should still work. The blog post has a video walkthrough that may be helpful as well.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.crumplab.com/blog/post_887_8_25_22_quartoblog/" class="uri">https://www.crumplab.com/blog/post_887_8_25_22_quartoblog/</a></p>
</section>
<section id="send-me-your-github-repo" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="send-me-your-github-repo">Send me your github repo</h2>
<p>If you get everything working, then you will have a github repository for your blog. Please send me the URL for this repository once you have it. We will be sharing code over github throughout this course.</p>
<p>For example, the github repo for this course website is:</p>
<p>&lt;&gt;</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/1_Getting_started/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
