<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>psyc2001</title>
<link>https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.353</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Week 3: JsPsych and the simple reaction time tutorial</title>
  <dc:creator>Matt Crump</dc:creator>
  <link>https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/3_jspsych_tutorial/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>Pre-requisites:</p>
<p>Have followed along from the previous posts</p>
<div class="quarto-video ratio ratio-16x9"><iframe data-external="1" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9IhmZbnQJJQ" title="" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
<section id="concepts-to-cover" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="concepts-to-cover">Concepts to cover</h2>
<p>I’ll cover the following concepts in the screencast and show how I am using software as I go along.</p>
<ul>
<li>What is JsPsych?
<ul>
<li>Overview of the <a href="https://www.jspsych.org/7.3/">JsPsych documentation</a> website</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Getting JsPsych on your computer
<ul>
<li>downloading the <a href="https://github.com/jspsych/jsPsych">library from github</a></li>
<li>Or, using links</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Simple reaction time tasks
<ul>
<li>Donders and subtractive logic</li>
<li>Reading: <a href="https://www.crumplab.com/cognition/textbook/C7_Information_Processing.html#donders-processing-stages" class="uri">https://www.crumplab.com/cognition/textbook/C7_Information_Processing.html#donders-processing-stages</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Walkthrough of the JsPsych simpleRT demo.</li>
</ul>
<section id="example-of-showing-the-code-works" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="example-of-showing-the-code-works">Example of showing the code works</h3>
<p><a href="test.html">Link to test.html</a></p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="assignment" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="assignment">Assignment</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>Show that you can get the JsPsych simple RT demo working and posted to your blog. You should be able to do this based on following along with the documentation and the screencast.</p></li>
<li><p>Generalize: The reading about Donder’s concept of processing stages discussed three kinds of tasks</p></li>
</ol>
<ol type="a">
<li>A basic detection task</li>
<li>A Go/NO-GO task</li>
<li>A choice reaction time task</li>
</ol>
<p>Your assignment is to attempt to produce scripts for each of these tasks by modifying the example simple RT demo script.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Psyc 2001</category>
  <category>jspsych</category>
  <guid>https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/3_jspsych_tutorial/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/3_jspsych_tutorial/week3.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Week 2: Really Basic HTML and Javascript</title>
  <dc:creator>Matt Crump</dc:creator>
  <link>https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/2_Basic_web/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>Pre-requisites:</p>
<p>This post assumes that you have a quarto blog up and running (see last post).</p>
<section id="overview" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="overview">Overview</h2>
<p>The purpose of this week is to make sure we understand some very basic web programming concepts before attempting to code cognitive psych experiments with jsPsych.</p>
<p>If you already have experience coding for the web, that’s great, and this may be a review for you.</p>
</section>
<section id="software" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="software">Software</h2>
<p>You should already have R Studio and R installed, as well as Github desktop. We will be using these tools throughout the course.</p>
<p>To program for the web you really only need a text editor (to write the code), and web-browser (to check that it works). We will use the text editor inside R studio (it’s totally fine if you want to use a different one). My preferred web-browser for debugging code is <a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/">firefox</a>. Google chrome is fine too. Safari for mac is OK.</p>
</section>
<section id="concepts-to-cover" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="concepts-to-cover">Concepts to cover</h2>
<div class="quarto-video ratio ratio-16x9"><iframe data-external="1" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bzFZtsc4Wl4" title="" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
<p>I’ll cover the following concepts in the screencast, and show how I am using software as I go along.</p>
<ul>
<li><p>What is HTML? What kind of file is it?</p></li>
<li><p>Web-browser as a compiler that interprets HTML code and displays it as a web page</p></li>
<li><p>Basic anatomy of an HTML file</p></li>
<li><p>Adding HTML elements to the body</p>
<ul>
<li>see <a href="https://www.w3schools.com/html/default.asp">w3schools</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><p>What is Javascript?</p></li>
<li><p>Web-browser as a javascript compiler that executes javascript code</p></li>
<li><p>Javascript control over HTML elements (changing webpages with javascript, recording webpage interactions with javascript)</p></li>
</ul>
<p><a href="test.html">Link to text.html</a></p>
</section>
<section id="assignment" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="assignment">Assignment</h2>
<p>Create your own basic html file. Explore the process of adding different kinds of html elements to it. See if you can program some kind of javascript interaction, even if it is super simple (e.g., like pressing a button changes something on the website).</p>
<p>Add your html file to your blog post so that it is viewable from your blog, and so that the code is viewable from github.</p>
<section id="example-assignment-ideas" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="example-assignment-ideas">Example assignment ideas</h3>
<p>In a couple weeks we will be making a Stroop experiment demo. Part of this experiment requires being able to present words one at a time in different colors.</p>
<p>These are some example stimuli:</p>
<p><img src="https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/2_Basic_web/Stroop.png" class="img-fluid"> Consider how you would use basic javascript and a button to achieve the following result:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Every time you click the button a new Stroop item is displayed on the screen.</li>
</ol>
<p>We will do this later using jsPsych, but it can be instructive to figure out how to solve problems using basic javascript and html.</p>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>Psyc 2001</category>
  <category>jspsych</category>
  <guid>https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/2_Basic_web/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/2_Basic_web/Basic.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Week 1: Installing software and getting your Quarto Blog working</title>
  <dc:creator>Matt Crump</dc:creator>
  <link>https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/1_Getting_started/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 



<p>Hi Everyone,</p>
<p>As we discussed in our meeting a goal for this week is for everyone to get a Quarto blog up and running. You will use this blog throughout the semester as a lab journal. Every week this blog will be a place where you place your work (along with making notes for yourself about what you are doing).</p>
<p>We will use R, R Studio, Quarto, and Github to create the blog. These very same tools will be used for several other purposes including coding experiments and analyzing data from them.</p>
<p>This post contains instructions for getting a quarto blog up and running. If you can’t get something to work and have spend more than 30 minutes trying to solve the problem, then please email me and I will help you!</p>
<section id="setting-up-your-quarto-blog" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="setting-up-your-quarto-blog">Setting up your quarto blog</h2>
<p>I wrote a blog post about how to do this a year ago. Here is the link. All of the steps should still work. The blog post has a video walk through that should be helpful as well.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.crumplab.com/blog/post_887_8_25_22_quartoblog/" class="uri">https://www.crumplab.com/blog/post_887_8_25_22_quartoblog/</a></p>
</section>
<section id="make-a-first-post" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="make-a-first-post">Make a first post</h2>
<p>If you get everything working then you should be able to create new posts and delete the example posts. Make at least one new post to demonstrate for yourself that it works.</p>
<p>I find blogging very helpful for learning new skills. For example, I’ll often use a blog post as a scratch pad to take notes or make observations about something that I’m trying to learn about. These notes often become helpful for me later on. I suggest that you write a blog post that contains notes about setting up your blog. This could include questions you have, notes about something that didn’t work, or ideas for things about the site you might want to change later.</p>
</section>
<section id="send-me-your-github-repo" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="send-me-your-github-repo">Send me your github repo</h2>
<p>If you get everything working, then you will have a github repository for your blog. Please send me the URL for this repository once you have it. We will be sharing code over github throughout this course.</p>
<p>For example, the github repo for this course website is:</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/CrumpLab/psyc2001" class="uri">https://github.com/CrumpLab/psyc2001</a></p>
</section>
<section id="feel-free-to-poke-around-quarto" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="feel-free-to-poke-around-quarto">Feel free to poke around Quarto</h2>
<p>The documentation for quarto is available here:</p>
<p><a href="https://quarto.org" class="uri">https://quarto.org</a></p>
<p>There is much more to quarto than making blogs, so feel free to poke around in the documentation to see what it can do.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/1_Getting_started/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://crumplab.com/psyc2001/blog/1_Getting_started/quarto.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="144" width="144"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
